#### **Summary**

Cesar Kyle Casil received his Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science from the University of California, Santa Cruz and is now practicing full stack web development in iOS and using the MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack. Since coming from both an accredited university and a coding bootcamp, he has not only acquired a unique set of skills, but has learned the importance of how they lead to success within the tech industry. Both institutions provided experience in working and leading small teams using agile software programming. His primary goal is to contribute his passion for programming towards a company's vision while expanding on his technical skills.

### Education

#### University of California, Santa Cruz

Mar 2019

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Coding Dojo, Silicon Valley, CA

Miscellaneous:

Apr 2018

Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Developer: Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack development

• Web development bootcamp specializing in front-end fundamentals as well as three full stacks. Dedicated over 1200+ hours of coding experience, including the ability to deploy a full website from client to server to database.

#### **Technical** Skills

JavaScript (ES6)/TypeScript, Swift, Python, LATEX <u>L</u>anguages: Front-End:

HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, JSON, HTTP Re-

quest/Response

MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose.js, Django Database:

ORM, Core Data, CRUD operations

Frameworks and Libraries: Angular, React, Node.js, Socket.IO, Express.js, Django, Flask Development Tools: Git, Microsoft Visual Studio, Xcode, Amazon Web Services

> (EC2), NGINX, Postman, Node Package Manager (NPM) Agile Scrum Methodology, Algorithms and Data Structures, Linux/Unix, Software Deployment (AWS), RESTful Ar-

> chitecture/API, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Model View Controller (MVC), Microsoft Office

#### Experience

### **VeEX Inc.**, Web Development Engineer, Fremont, CA

Apr 2019-Present

- Managed numerous virtual machines for application and server use
- Maintained company website by creating new product pages, press releases, and trade show announcements
- Implemented entirely new web framework (Angular) and migrated outdated source code to create a clean and fast website that conforms to web standards
- Notable Technologies: PmWiki, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular/TypeScript, Bootstrap, MySQL, Excel, GitHub, Apache, SEO, Google Analytics, Windows Server, Linux

Freelance Web Developer, Santa Clara, CA

 $\operatorname{Jan}\ 2018\text{--}\operatorname{Jan}\ 2019$ 

- Built full-stack, modern, responsive web applications while providing quick feedback and sup-
- Lead a small team in collaboration with clients in order to create websites from the ground up

#### MissionU, Research Intern, San Francisco, CA

Mar 2017–May 2017

- Collaborated in a small team to present a roadshow plan to reach out to local schools and community centers for brand launch
- Drafted 4 research documents from various sources that suggest 1.3 million new job postings in 2020 with skills in data science and analytics
- Curated 4 excel spreadsheets containing 151 subject matter experts, employer partner leads, and various professors to gain input on MissionU's curriculum for the data analyst program

### Garcon LLC, Android Developer Intern, Santa Clara, CA

Sept 2016–Dec 2016

- Translated UI mockups into a working, interactive Android application using Android Studio and Java during its early stages
- Designed and created a functional implementation of the mobile applications interface
- Testing and quality assurance

## **Projects**

## Tips and Templates

Oct 2018–Ongoing

Notes on various topics based around Computer Science.

• Technologies Used: Markdown, Git

Cesar Kyle Casil Personal Portfolio.

Jan 2018-Ongoing

sign (RWD), Font Awesome, Google Analytics, Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Alex the Party Paused

• Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap 4, Responsive Web De-

E-commerce website selling photo prints. Takes customer from store front to cart to checkout. • Technologies Used: Angular, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3,

Bootstrap 4, Responsive Web Design (RWD), Amazon EC2, Multer

# Megumi Hiramoto

Sept 2018-Dec 2018

Portfolio for Academy of Art student to display her studies in Fashion Journalism.

• Technologies Used: React, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Responsive Wed Design (RWD), GoDaddy

# Love Changing the World, Inc.

Jun 2018-Oct 2018

Public website for the non-profit organization Love Changing the World, Inc. Allows donations through PayPal in exchange for apparel with LCTW branding. • Technologies Used: React, Redux, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, Bootstrap 4, HTML5,

CSS3, JavaScript, Google Maps API, PayPal API Apr 2018-Ongoing

Personal iOS application to aid in daily workout programs. Includes a user profile, kg/lb conversion

calculator, and a log of main lifts. • Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift 5, Core Data, Auto Layout, Firebase, Google AdMob, Icons8

# Dojo Attendance Tracker

Mar 2018

iOS application that records the amount of time spent inside Coding Dojo as well as the time spent outside; can be expanded into an attendance tracker for Coding Dojo. • Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift 4, Core Location, Map Kit, AV Foundation, Core Data,

Auto Layout

# Baskin-Robbins Birthday 31

Feb 2018

Web application tailored to Baskin-Robbins fans. Allows the registered user to view and add all the available flavors to a list of favorites, and uses location to find the nearest Baskin-Robbins through the Google Maps API. • Technologies Used: Python, Django, SQLite3, Google Maps JavaScript API, Bcrypt, HTML5,

CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap 4, Object Relational Mapping (ORM), Object Oriented Programming (OOP)

### Positions & Affiliations

Leadership

Lambda Phi Epsilon, Webmaster/Academics/Fundraiser Chair University of California, Santa Cruz

Mar 2014–Jun 2016

- Created and maintained chapter website
- Kept in close contact with members to promote excellence in academics Focused on raising money for activities and services